

Michael Koch

Software Developer

With over three years of exceptional software development experience, I bring a proven track record of continuous learning and a versatile skillset, enabling me to make an immediate impact and add value from day one. My strong interpersonal and collaborative skills allow me to effectively collaborate with team members, facilitate discussions on project requirements, and assume leadership roles in ensuring the successful deliver of projects.



856-404-8845



mkoch@michaelgkoch.com



linkedin.com/in/michaelgkochh



@MichaelKochDev

Website:

michaelgkoch.com

SKILLS:

JavaScript Java React C# SQL

•••

Professional Experience

March 2024 - Present

Freelance Software Development

As a freelance software developer, my projects and responsibilities include:

- Developing a cross-platform music industry app using react native, enabling artists to share and sell their music and merchandise directly to their fans
- Working in a startup-like environment, taking on responsibilities beyond development, including deciding new features and company direction
- Acting as the primary developer of a dream interpretation website and being responsible for shipping new features directly to users
- Designed and developed a seamless, intuitive user interface for effortless navigation and interaction
- Architected a secure database from the ground up to safely store user profiles and information

Experience: NextJS 14, Tailwind CSS, MongoDB, APIs, AI (LLMs), React, React Native

March 2023 – Present

Associate Software Engineer @ JP Morgan Chase

As an Associate Software Engineer for JP Morgan Chase, I am responsible for:

- Acting as Lead Front-End Developer by overseeing and producing all aspects related to user interface development.
- Accomplishing implementation upgrades to our UI, enabling users to perform more accurate data updates.
- Streamlining testing processes within our application, leading to more robust code coverage and efficient deployments
- Development of sophisticated automated functional tests to ensure proper integration and performance between our UI and API
- Maintenance of our CI/CD pipelines, resulting in effective deployments to production **Experience**: React, Spring Boot, CI/CD, Junit, SQL, AWS, TDD, Agile, APIs

May 2021 – March 2023

Software Developer @ CCLR

As a Software Developer for CCLR, I am responsible for:

- Managing the automation and interconnection of multiple departments, leading to enhanced productivity and reduced human error.
- Expanding revenue streams by performing R&D on hand-serving automation.
- Developing complex SQL queries of business data, while concurrently building an intuitive user interface for data visualization and manipulation
- Collaborating with management and employees to define business requirements, and subsequentially deliver successfully on said requirements

Experience: JavaScript, ASP.NET, C#, jQuery, SQL, HTML

June 2020 – August 2020

Web Development Intern @ Maxeta Technologies Inc.

As a Web Development Intern for Maxeta Technologies Inc., I am responsible for:

- Working with clients to outline and understand business problems.
- Helping develop an application that automates day-to-day tasks of client's employees, improving efficiency and organization company-wide.

Experience: Typescript, Angular

Education

2017 - 2021 - Philadelphia

Temple University

BS In Computer Engineering & Minor in Computer Science

Started by studying computer engineering because of my fascination with computers, but as I learned about both the hardware and software aspect of computers, I inevitably learned that software development was where my deeper interest lied, and quickly picked up an additional minor in computer science.

2022 - Online

Coursera

Machine Learning/AI Fundamentals